{
    "glossary": {
        "title": "1982.5",
        "season": "Höst",
        "glossaryList":[
            {
                "number": "1",
                "question": "fingerad",
                "a": "upprepad",
                "b": "låtsad",
                "c": "ändrad",
                "d": "avklarad",
                "e": "fastställd",
                "answer": "låtsad"
            },
            {
                "number": "2",
                "question": "honorar",
                "a": "hälsning",
                "b": "uppvisning",
                "c": "betalning",
                "d": "uppvaktning",
                "e": "insamling",
                "answer": "betalning"
            },
            {
                "number": "3",
                "question": "makulera",
                "a": "erbjuda",
                "b": "beräkna",
                "c": "överklaga",
                "d": "förstöra",
                "e": "återsända",
                "answer": "förstöra"
            },
            {
                "number": "4",
                "question": "ockult",
                "a": "oäkta",
                "b": "övernaturlig",
                "c": "opassande",
                "d": "enastående",
                "e": "finurlig",
                "answer": "övernaturlig"
            },
            {
                "number": "5",
                "question": "erodera",
                "a": "ilskna till",
                "b": "ta isär",
                "c": "nöta bort",
                "d": "stöta ut",
                "e": "missta sig",
                "answer": "nöta bort"
            },
            {
                "number": "6",
                "question": "uniformitet",
                "a": "folklighet",
                "b": "oformlighet",
                "c": "giltighet",
                "d": "överlägsenhet",
                "e": "likformighet",
                "answer": "likformighet"
            },
            {
                "number": "7",
                "question": "kryptisk",
                "a": "hemlighetsfull",
                "b": "snål",
                "c": "översvallande",
                "d": "nedstämd",
                "e": "omständlig",
                "answer": "hemlighetsfull"
            },
            {
                "number": "8",
                "question": "reinkarnation",
                "a": "återfall",
                "b": "bortstötning",
                "c": "tillfrisknande",
                "d": "återfödelse",
                "e": "insjuknande",
                "answer": "återfödelse"
            },
            {
                "number": "9",
                "question": "universell",
                "a": "enskild",
                "b": "påtaglig",
                "c": "allomfattande",
                "d": "överskådlig",
                "e": "ändamålsenlig",
                "answer": "allomfattande"
            },
            {
                "number": "10",
                "question": "turbulens",
                "a": "virvelrörelse",
                "b": "utvidgning",
                "c": "inbromsning",
                "d": "kortslutning",
                "e": "färgskiftning",
                "answer": "virvelrörelse"
            },
            {
                "number": "11",
                "question": "vitrin",
                "a": "utställningsskåp",
                "b": "giftblandning",
                "c": "bakverk",
                "d": "färgämne",
                "e": "avloppssystem",
                "answer": "utställningsskåp"
            },
            {
                "number": "12",
                "question": "hörsamma",
                "a": "förtydliga",
                "b": "befalla",
                "c": "åhöra",
                "d": "förnimma",
                "e": "lyda",
                "answer": "lyda"
            },
            {
                "number": "13",
                "question": "stereotyp",
                "a": "noggrann",
                "b": "otillräknelig",
                "c": "slarvig",
                "d": "tveksam",
                "e": "oföränderlig",
                "answer": "oföränderlig"
            },
            {
                "number": "14",
                "question": "forte",
                "a": "svagt",
                "b": "stötvis",
                "c": "snabbt",
                "d": "starkt",
                "e": "sakta",
                "answer": "starkt"
            },
            {
                "number": "15",
                "question": "symbios",
                "a": "åtskillnad",
                "b": "samlevnad",
                "c": "motstånd",
                "d": "medhåll",
                "e": "självständighet",
                "answer": "samlevnad"
            },
            {
                "number": "16",
                "question": "skrodera",
                "a": "pryda",
                "b": "förarga",
                "c": "skryta",
                "d": "baktala",
                "e": "skrämma",
                "answer": "skryta"
            },
            {
                "number": "17",
                "question": "talisman",
                "a": "soffa",
                "b": "trollkarl",
                "c": "krigare",
                "d": "skyddsföremål",
                "e": "helgedom",
                "answer": "skyddsföremål"
            },
            {
                "number": "18",
                "question": "nagelfara",
                "a": "reta",
                "b": "lura",
                "c": "granska",
                "d": "betvivla",
                "e": "nedgöra",
                "answer": "granska"
            },
            {
                "number": "19",
                "question": "beivra",
                "a": "ingripa mot",
                "b": "skynda på",
                "c": "förolämpa",
                "d": "utmana",
                "e": "uppmuntra till",
                "answer": "ingripa mot"
            },
            {
                "number": "20",
                "question": "diarium",
                "a": "vattenbehållare",
                "b": "ormgrop",
                "c": "uppskov",
                "d": "dagbok",
                "e": "räkning",
                "answer": "dagbok"
            },
            {
                "number": "21",
                "question": "interaktion",
                "a": "utrop",
                "b": "avsikt",
                "c": "omtagning",
                "d": "förfrågan",
                "e": "växelspel",
                "answer": "växelspel"
            },
            {
                "number": "22",
                "question": "konsolidera",
                "a": "upprusta",
                "b": "förstärka",
                "c": "begrunda",
                "d": "tillerkänna",
                "e": "förhandla",
                "answer": "förstärka"
            },
            {
                "number": "23",
                "question": "defaitism",
                "a": "modlöshet",
                "b": "inställsamhet",
                "c": "ofullständighet",
                "d": "efterblivenhet",
                "e": "ålderssvaghet",
                "answer": "modlöshet"
            },
            {
                "number": "24",
                "question": "bilateral",
                "a": "ostadig",
                "b": "oegennyttig",
                "c": "ömsesidig",
                "d": "planmässig",
                "e": "tvetydlig",
                "answer": "ömsesidig"
            },
            {
                "number": "25",
                "question": "skrupler",
                "a": "baktankar",
                "b": "motsättningar",
                "c": "oförrätter",
                "d": "förevändningar",
                "e": "betänkligheter",
                "answer": "betänkligheter"
            },
            {
                "number": "26",
                "question": "enlevera",
                "a": "avskeda",
                "b": "bortföra",
                "c": "utlämna",
                "d": "anlita",
                "e": "överge",
                "answer": "bortföra"
            },
            {
                "number": "27",
                "question": "bifurkation",
                "a": "urgröpning",
                "b": "anhopning",
                "c": "avsärrning",
                "d": "förgrening",
                "e": "förvisning",
                "answer": "förgrening"
            },
            {
                "number": "28",
                "question": "nekrolog",
                "a": "oregelverk",
                "b": "dödsruna",
                "c": "vattenväxt",
                "d": "talarstol",
                "e": "köpebrev",
                "answer": "dödsruna"
            },
            {
                "number": "29",
                "question": "koncession",
                "a": "tillbakagång",
                "b": "tillkomst",
                "c": "tillstånd",
                "d": "tillfällighet",
                "e": "tillrättavisning",
                "answer": "tillstånd"
            },
            {
                "number": "30",
                "question": "perenn",
                "a": "flerårig",
                "b": "högtidlig",
                "c": "välfylld",
                "d": "fulländad",
                "e": "tillfällig",
                "answer": "flerårig"
            }
        ]
    }
}